本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
I have a favor to ask of you two.
お二人にお願いがあるのです
I want you to take Yun with you on your journey.
ユン君も旅に連れて行って欲しい
Episode 8:   The Chosen Door
Yun, did you make these clothes?
この服ユンが作ったの
Not really. I just had some leftover cloth.
別に 布が余ってたから
As a princess, you probably want
nothing less than silk,
絹じゃないから お姫様は不満だろうけど
前のボロより増しだろう
but it's better than those rags you had on.
面白い服 気に入った
I love these interesting clothes!
面白い服
Interesting clothes?
Hey, lend me something sharp.
ね 何か切る道具 貸して
髪 揃える
I'm going to even out my hair.
With that?!
それで
ったく 面倒くさい
Jeez, what a pain.
これだからお姫様は...
This is why I hate princesses.
You can do anything, can't you, Yun?
ユンって何でも出来るのね
手のかかる神官が居るからね
Because I have that troublesome
priest to take care of.
彼奴がけがばかりするから 医術覚えたし
I learned medicine because
he constantly hurts himself,
and I've mastered cooking.
料理も完璧
欠点と言えば 美少年過ぎるくらいだね
My only flaw is that I'm far too handsome.
I didn't ask about that.
それは聞いてない
でも 優しいね
You're kind, though.
Huh?
イクスの事もだけど
You're kind to Ik-su too.
王族が嫌いだって言ったのに 私の髪 切ってくれてる
But you're cutting my hair,
even though you said you hated royalty.
Just so you know, this isn't free.
有料だよ 言っとくけど
You owe me for the medicine,
clothes, and the haircut.
治療代とか服代とか散髪も
えっと
Um...
ムンドクに付けといて
Bill it to Mun-deok!
ムンドク 風の部族の英雄じゃん
Mun-deok?! He's the Wind Tribe's hero!
Mun-deok's a hero?
ムンドクって英雄なの
バカ ムンドクって言ったら
Idiot! Mun-deok was a powerful commander,
just as strong as Yu-hon.
あのユホンと並び称される最強の武将だったんだから
He was? The Mun-deok I know is an
old man who loves his children.
そうなんだ 私の知ってるムンドクは
子供思いのお爺さんだから
Jeez.
まったく
終わったよ
I'm finished.
ありがとう
Thank you.
ユンって何でも知ってるよね
You know everything, Yun.
I can't help it. I'm a genius.
天才だから仕方ない
本は一回読めば暗記できるし
I can memorize books after reading them once.
That's amazing.
凄い
でも俺が読んだのは一部の本だけ
But I've only read a few books.
世界には俺が知らない本がたくさんある
There are tons of books I'm not
familiar with in the world.
むかつく
It makes me angry.
読んでみたい
Would you like to read them?
そりゃね
Of course.
あのね ユン
Listen, Yun.
It's not a problem, though.
ま でも問題ないよ
本は少しつつ集めるし
I can collect books bit by bit.
俺は当分 この汚い本でいいや
And I'll be satisfied with this filthy book for a while.
Which one is it?
その本は
イクスのバカが私の為につってゴミから漁ってきたり
That idiot Ik-su dug it out of the garbage for me,
何もない所で転んで破ったり
then tore it when he tripped over nothing.
恐れべきドジね
He's incredibly clumsy.
He's stupid, isn't he?
間抜けだろ
All his "God" business might seem phony,
神だ何だって胡散臭いけど
but I know better than anyone that he can't...
彼奴が嘘付けない奴だってのは俺が一番知ってる...し
lie.
と とにかく 旅に出るならとっとと行っちゃてよね
I-In any case, if you're leaving
on a journey, get out of here.
I don't have time to look after you two.
俺 あんたらの面倒を見る暇ないし
イクス
Ik-su.
姫様
Princess.
Those clothes are beautiful.
その服 素敵です
You look great in them.
とてもお似合いです
ユン君ですね
Yun made them, didn't he?
He's an incredible boy.
あの子は本当にすごい
Yes.
それでどうでしたかユン君は
Anyway, what did Yun say?
イクスって 私の父上に似てる
Ik-su, you're a lot like my father.
Huh? You mean King Il?
え イル陛下ですか
Yes.
そんな 恐れ多い
You're too generous.
頼りなくて泣き虫で頭に花咲がいてて
You're unreliable, a crybaby,
and your head is in the clouds.
でも 可愛い人
But you're a cute person.
ね イクス
Hey, Ik-su...
Yes.
はい
Yun is foul-mouthed, but he loves you.
ユンは口は悪いけど 貴方の事が大好きだもの
私は家族を引き離したくない
I don't want to pull a family apart.
ユンを旅には連れていけないよ
I can't take Yun with us on our journey.
だから イクスのお願いは聞けない
So I can't comply with your request.
イクスのお願い
Ik-su's request?
イクスはユンを連れて行ってって言ったけど やっぱり私
You asked me to take Yun with us, but...
ユンが行くと言わない限り 連れて行けない
unless Yun says he wants to go,
I can't take him with us.
ですね
You're right.
ごめんなさい 僕が言うべきでした
I'm sorry. I should have been
the one to say that.
Ouch...
ユン君
Yun.
ちょうどよかった 今ね...
Good timing. I was just-
何 今の話 俺に何処行けって
What was that conversation about?
Where do you want me to go?
彼奴等と一緒に行けって
You want me to go with them?!
Yun, I want you to leave this place
and assist the princess and her friend.
ユン君 君はここを出て 姫達の手助けをしてあげて
何で俺が 冗談じゃないよ
Why me? You can't be serious!
君はこんな所に居ていい子じゃない
You shouldn't stay here.
世界を見て置いて
Go see the world.
イクス
Ik-su...
僕なら君が居なくても平気だし
I'll be fine without you.
RAGE
あの野郎
That jerk.
勝手な事言って
How dare he say that?
ユン君 これ見て 医学の本
Yun, look. It's a book of medicine.
Go see the world.
世界を見て置いて
Let me fry these fish.
魚 焼かせろ
もうそんなに動けるようになったの
You can already move around that much?
俺は不死身だ つっか死ねねぇ
I'm immortal. Actually, I can't afford to die.
I have to look after a troublesome princess.
世話の焼けるお姫さんが居るんだな
なんで
Why?
自分の命を危険に晒してまで
お姫様を守る何て バカじゃないの
You must be stupid to risk your
life protecting a princess.
When you protect someone
you want to keep safe,
おめぇは守りたい者を守る時
いちいちてめぇの命と天秤にかけるのか
do you always weigh your
own life against theirs?
魚 食う
Want some fish?
要らない
No.
チクショウ
Damn it.
-Seven Years Earlier-
Fire Tribe Region, Toka Village
Someone help!
Yesterday, I ate tree roots.
昨日 口にしたのは木の根っこ
畑には作物どころか 虫さえいない
The fields have no crops or even insects.
Today, I'll steal food.
今日は奪おう 食べ物を
前やった時は 逆に殺されかけた
Last time I did it, I nearly got killed.
This time, I'll do it right.
I'll do it in one strike.
今度はうまくやろう 一撃だ
死んだっていいんだ
I don't care if I die.
よし
All right.
金 金 食い物
Money. Money! Food!
ごめん...何も...ない
I'm sorry. I don't have anything.
う 動くな
D-Don't move!
君は さっきの...
You're that boy.
Everyone in the village
has been talking about it.
村で噂になってる
最近 金の粒を持った余所者がうろついてるって
Recently, there's been an outsider
wandering around with bits of gold.
It's you, isn't it? Give them to me!
あんただろ 出せ
C-Crying won't help you!
泣いても ダメだから
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
金の粒はさっき別の子にあげてしまって
I just gave some gold to another child.
That was the last of it.
それが最後だったんだ
でも 今度なにが見つけたら
絶対君の所に持ってくるね
But if I find something good again,
I'll definitely bring it to you.
Huh?
あれ
あんたがボートしてるから悪いんだ
It's your fault for spacing out.
ここは食うか食われるか何だよ
This is a dog-eat-dog world!
大丈夫 痛くない
It's all right. It doesn't hurt.
Don't worry.
心配しないで
Why would I worry about you?
心配なんかする訳ないだろ
I almost killed you just now!
あんた今 俺に殺されかけてんだよ
Well, then, please excuse me.
ではでは お邪魔しました
話 聞いてる
Are you even listening?
H-Hold on! We aren't done discussing
those pieces of gold!
ちょっと 金の粒の話はまだ終わってないよ
You're staying with me today!
今日はうちに居て貰うから
I'm delighted. I'd actually planned
to camp out tonight.
嬉しいな 実は野宿するつもりだったんで
My name is Ik-su.
僕 イクスと申します
あったかい 生きてる
He's warm. He's alive.
これを塗って置けば
If I rub this on...
寒い 腹へった
It's cold. I'm hungry.
俺 ここで死ぬのかな
Am I going to die here?
芋だ
A potato!
あげる
For you.
Where did you get this?
Did you steal it?
どうしたのこれ 盗んだ
頂いた
I received it.
I haven't eaten a potato in so long.
芋なんて久しぶり
あんた どうしたの
What happened to you?
靴は
Where are your shoes?
芋と交換して貰っちゃった
I traded them for a potato.
交換して貰ったって
You traded them?
この寒いなか なにやってんの
What are you doing?
It's cold out there.
Why would you go so far for me?
俺なんかにそこまでする
Are you really up to something?
なにか裏があるんじゃ
だって
I just...
頭に薬を塗ってくれたお礼
had to thank you for applying
medicine to my head.
You were awake?
起きてたのかよ
Yeah, it's working well.
うん よく聞いてる
心がぽかぽかあったかくて
My heart feels warm.
なんだか 目頭まで熱くなっ...
Even the corners of my eyes feel hot.
なんで泣くの
Why are you crying?
変な奴
You're weird.
外の人間って 皆そうなの
Are all outsiders like you?
外にはいろんな人が居る
There are all kinds of people outside.
I don't go to the capital often, though.
僕はあまり都には行かないけど
都
The capital?
Do you want to go to the capital?
都に行きたいの
Yeah!
早くここを出て 都や他の土地に行きたい
I want to leave this place and go
to the capital and other regions.
大きくなったら 本もいっぱい読んで
自由に勉強出来る所に行きたい
Once I grow up, I want to go where I can
read lots of books and study freely.
本 読めるんだ
You can read?
当然
Of course.
That's impressive.
凄いね
簡単な本ならだけど
Just simple books, though.
Someday, I'll learn to read difficult books.
難しい本だって 何時か
I'll find you a book, then.
じゃ 今度は本を探してくるね
I travel all over the place.
色んなとこ 転々としてるから
Huh? What kind of work do you do?
え あんた何してる人
神様に祈る人
I'm someone who prays to God.
神様
To God?
Yes.
神様の声をたよりに 元気がない人訪ねて
The voice of God leads me to
people who are feeling down.
その人が生きる勇気を手に入れるお手伝いするの
I help those people find the courage to live.
God doesn't exist.
居る訳ないよ 神様なんか
居る訳ないのに 嘘つきには見えない
There's no way God exists,
but he doesn't seem like a liar.
これからどっか行くのか 裸足で大丈夫
Are you going somewhere now?
Will you be okay without shoes?
I'll make some from straw. I'll be fine.
草鞋作るから平気
Straw?
草鞋？
I was taught how to do it long ago.
昔教えて貰ったの
T-Teach me!
俺にも教えて
ユン君 すごい
Amazing, Yun.
It's your first time making them,
but you could easily sell these.
初めてなのに 売り物見たいな草鞋だね
あんたのは草鞋に謝れってくらい酷いな
Yours are so awful, you should
apologize to the straw.
一つ覚えた
I learned something!
You can have these.
これあげる
Are you sure? These sandals are so nice.
え いいの 立派な草鞋
その代わり また何か教えて
In exchange, teach me something else.
だ 大丈夫
A-Are you okay?
I'm fine!
大丈夫だ
楽しかった もっともっと話したかった
That was fun. I wish I could
have talked to him more.
聞きたい事 あったのに
There are so many things I wanted to ask.
I didn't really want him to go,
but I couldn't say it.
本当は行かないでほしかったのに 言えなかった
Next time... Next time we meet,
maybe I'll ask him...
今度来たら 今度会えたら 言って見ようか
ここに居てって
to stay here.
Maybe he'll think I'm a nuisance...
面倒だと思われるかな
But that's okay. Please come back soon.
しれでもいい 早くきて
どうしてくれる
How will you make this up to me?
一人なんていつもだったのに
I was always alone before.
But since I met you, I've been
so lonely, I can't stand it.
あんたに会って 寂しくて仕方ないじゃないか
Ik-su! What happened to you? You're hurt!
イクス どうしたんだよそのけが
You're so lightly dressed, too.
それに そんな薄着
ごめんね 来るのが遅くなって
I'm sorry it took me so long to come back here.
Don't worry about that.
そんな事
たくさん色んなものあげたくて集めてたら
I wanted to give you lots of things,
but as I was gathering them,
some people who wanted my
gold took all my belongings.
金の粒を狙う人達に持ち物取られて
本もなくなっちゃった
Even the books are gone.
金の粒は もう一粒も残ってなかったんだけ
I don't have a single piece of gold left.
ユン君 僕 遠くへ行くよ
Yun, I'm going far away.
Huh?
僕は人と居たいけど
I want to be around people,
but when I have gold,
金の粒を持ってた僕は人にとって良くないものを呼び寄せる
it brings out something unpleasant in them.
最後に顔が見たかった
I wanted to see your face before I left.
I really enjoyed making sandals with you.
君と草鞋を作るのがとても楽しかったから
さよなら
Goodbye.
行く
I'll go.
I'll go with you.
俺も行く
But I have to keep a low profile.
でも僕はあまり表には出られなくて
I can't go to the capital, and your books...
都には行けないし 本だって...
It's fine. I don't have to go to the capital.
いい 都に行かなくてもいい
本がなくてもいい
I don't need books, either!
You'll teach me!
イクスが教えてよ
だいたいあんたフラフラ危なっかしんだよ
Besides, you're so clumsy!
あんたに薬塗ってやれるのは俺くらいでしょう
Who else would apply your medicine for you?
外の世界...か
The outside world, huh?
な イクス 歴代の英雄の話聞かせて
Hey, Ik-su. Tell me about
the heroes of the past.
面倒くさい またけがしたのかよ
What a pain. You injured yourself again?
ちょっと待ってて 薬草を
Wait here. I'll get some herbs.
I know, but you're so clumsy.
分かってるよ
分かってるよ でも あんた危なっかしいじゃ
ユン君
Yun.
これ
Here.
Your sandals are coming apart, aren't they?
今の草鞋 もうぼろぼろでしょう
相変わらず下手くそだな
You're still as terrible at this as ever.
Huh? I've gotten pretty good at making them.
へ 大分上手に編めるようになってきたんだけど
イクスは
What about yours?
Huh?
イクスのだって ぼろぼろだろ
Yours are coming apart, too.
仕方ないな ちょっと待ってて
You're hopeless. Give me a minute.
凄いね ユン君は
You're amazing, Yun.
本当にすごい
Truly incredible.
ほら
Here.
ありがとう
Thank you.
ぴったり
They're perfect!
Look, look!
ね 見てみて
転ばなかった
I didn't fall.
転ばなかったよ
僕なら大丈夫
I'll be fine.
イクス
Ik-su, I know I called the princess naive,
俺 あのお姫様に世間知らずとか言ったけど
but she's actually just ignorant.
実は知識だけで 現実はなんも分かってないんだ...たぶん
She probably doesn't know anything about reality.
それって 格好悪い
It's so lame.
ユン君
Yun...
Ik-su, I bet you don't know that,
to me, your words are absolute.
な イクス 知らないだろ
俺にとって あんたの言葉は絶対なんだよ
So if you order me to go, I'll go.
だから結局 あんたが行けと命じるなら俺は行くんだ
それはきっと 俺の天命って奴でしょう
It must be God's will for me, right?
だいたいあんた もう俺が居なくても全然平気見たいだし
Besides, you seem like you'll be
totally fine without me now!
言葉には力があって
There is strength in words.
時にそれは 言霊になるんだ
Sometimes, they become words of power.
だから平気って言えば そりゃ誠となって平気になるかなと
I thought that if I said I'm fine,
then I really would be fine.
But it's no use. It doesn't work.
でも...ダメ 効かない
寂しくて...寂しくて...僕は
I'm so sad. I...
You're such a pain. It isn't the last
time we'll see each other.
面倒くさい 今生の別れじゃあるまいし
心は決まったのか
Have you made up your mind?
Yeah.
ハクも賛成してくれるよね
Hak, you approve, don't you?
誰かさんよりは荷物にならなそうだしな
He'll probably be less of a burden
than someone else I know.
誰かさんって誰
Who are you talking about?
さぁな
Who knows?
ユン君 大丈夫
Yun, will you be all right?
それを聞きたいのはこっちだよ
I could ask you the same thing.
ユン なにそんなに持ってるの
Yun, what's all that stuff you're bringing?
If they're books, leave them.
It's just more bulk.
本なら置いとけよ 嵩張るから
They're not books.
本じゃないよ
What is it, then? Let me see.
じゃなんだよ 見せてみろ
これはお姫様を入れて警備されてる町中なんかに入る為の袋
This is a bag we can put the princess in
when we enter cities that are guarded.
私を入れる
Put me in?
他にも色々用意してるけど 見る
I've got a bunch of other stuff.
Do you want to see it?
もういい 行くぞ
I've seen enough. Let's go.
We'll lose the daylight.
日が暮れちまう
Huh?
世話になったな
Thanks for taking care of us.
We'll see you later, Ik-su.
イクス 行ってきます
貴方達の無事を祈ります
I'll pray for your safe journey.
What the heck? You're the one
who told me to show you.
なんだよ 見せろってそっちから言ってきたくせに
いってらっしゃい
See you later.
Yeah.
Let's hurry. Before the sun sets,
we need to cross three mountains.
急ぐよ 日のあるうちに山を三つ越えないといけないからな
Yes.
Are you already ordering us around?
いきなり仕切りますか
天才美少年なんだから 当然でしょう
I'm a handsome genius. Of course I am.
黙ってついてきて
Shut up and follow me.
Yeah, yeah.
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
Father, if I do not take lives, I cannot live.
父上 奪わなければ 私は今 生きてゆけません
次回 暁のヨナ 第九話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 9:
Episode 9:   Shaking Resolve
Shaking Resolve.
ふるえる覚悟